MERIN YILMAZ

Junior Software Developer

merin.yilmaz@gmail.com - 07809 471 368 – Colchester, Essex GitHub: Merin-Yilmaz - LinkedIn: Merin-Yilmaz

Profile

Having always an interest and appreciation for tech, I took the plunge of taking it upon myself to begin my new career journey into software. I began with self-teaching through watching various tutorials and then was fortunate enough to be granted access on to a scholarship for Software Development. I've a creative eye and an interest in Front-End where I can transform the aesthetics of a page as well as improve user's experience.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Node.js

Testing: Test Driven Development (TDD), Jest, Supertest

Hosting: Netlify, Vercel

Front-End: HTML, CSS, SCSS, React.js, Next.js, Wordpress SQL, PSQL, Seeding, Migrations, MongoDB

Other: Paired programming, technical communication, SDL, Agile & SCRUM methodologies

Experience

Trainee Software Developer

11/2023 - 03/2024

Northcoders

During my time in this Software Development bootcamp, as well as learning languages like JavaScript, I also learned valuable skills such as pair programming, Agile methodologies and Test Driven Development to develop web applications. Projects I have worked on either by myself or with others are:

- Tipper: https://front-end-eight-eta-57.vercel.app/ GitHub Repo: https://github.com/Tipper-final-project A chashless tipping mobile web-app.
- NC News: https://github.com/Merin-Yilmaz/NC-News-FE
 The frontEnd of the social forum news site, where you can interact and discuss with various articles and other users.
- NC News API: https://github.com/Merin-Yilmaz/NC-News
 This is the backEnd API of a social forum news site.

Career Break

Personal Growth 04/2023 - 11/2023

- Due to a back injury, I took the time to work on gaining strength again in my back and core through exercise and yoga.
- Began looking in to front-end coding through online tutorials on Udemy.

Head Dog Groomer/Manager

11/2021 - 04/2023

Suffolk Dog Town

- Maintaining staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employee
- Ensuring a safe, secure and legal working environment through risk assessments, monitoring and training
- · Communicating job expectations by planning, monitoring and appraising

Lead Dog Groomer 11/2020 - 07/2021

Doggroomology

- Overseeing and maintaining website and social medias
- · Managing appointments and payments via telephone and booking system

Dog Groomer 06/2020 - 08/2020

Pet Universe Cat & Dog Grooming Salon

• Covering all aspects of pet dog grooming, completing from start to finish, whist delivering a high standard of pet grooming. Responsible for handling payments and managing appointments.

Trainee Dog Groomer

PetStock Prahran – Melbourne, Aus

Providing professional grooming to dogs of various breeds and sizes. Assisting on shop floor with customers as well as putting out stock.

09/2018 - 12/2019 **Career Break**

Travelling in Australia

Overall I travelled and worked abroad in Australia for 19months. During that time I had also:

- · Completed 3 months of Farm work which involved grape picking and orange packing in Redcliffs
- Completed an Intensive Dog Grooming course in Melbourne
- Made amazing, lifelong friends

Member Services Coordinator

02/2017 - 07/2018

The General Council of the Bar

• Managing communications with the Bar Council members, professionals and stakeholders, allocating enquiries as required within and across teams

Facilities Administrator

Parkinson's UK Charity

Liaising with external professionals such as insurance brokers, contractors and sundry suppliers

12/2011-08/2018 Relief Worker

Cheviots Children's Disability Service

Supervising children and young adults with special needs

Education & Qualifications

Professional Dog Grooming 11/2019 Dog Diversity Grooming School

BSc Psychology 06/2014

City University London 2:2

A Level: Psychology 06/2010

Chace Community School

Introduction to Counselling Skills 04/2010

Chace Community School Level 2

Hobbies & Interests

Travelling

 I enjoy to travel and explore different countries and cultures, meeting new people and trying different foods. I have backpacked around Thailand and went on a working-holiday in Australia. Explored Colombia, Fiji, Iceland and have been on an amazing safari trip in South Africa, Zimbabwe & Botswana.

Yoga

To ensure I maintain core strength, I practice yoga most days during the week, either at home, the gym or occasional classes

Pole Fitness

· I also go to pole fitness classes twice a week to keep on top of my back and core strength

09/2019 - 03/2020

01/2016 - 02/2017